When I read through the Revelation, I notice there appear to be two different groups
当我通读启示录时，我注意到似乎有两个不同的群体
of believers during the Great Tribulation.
大灾难期间的信徒。
Have you ever noticed that?
你有没有注意到这一点？
There's one group of 144,000 faithful followers of the Lamb. These people are mentioned in the Revelation.
有一群 144,000 名羔羊的忠实追随者。启示录中提到了这些人。
They include 12,000 people from each of 12 different tribes; and so I often refer to them as the 12 tribes.
他们包括来自 12 个不同部落的 12,000 人；所以我经常把他们称为 12 个部落。
But then John describes the second group.
但随后约翰描述了第二组。
The second group is a great multitude...more people than John had words to describe--probably millions
第二组是一大群人……比约翰能用语言来形容的人还要多——可能是数百万人
and they're crying out to God.
他们向上帝呼求。
In a 6th chapter of the Revelation, we learn more about them.
在启示录的第 6 章中，我们更多地了解了它们。
These white robes they're wearing appear to symbolize martyrdom.
他们穿着的这些白色长袍似乎象征着殉难。
Their souls cry out to God, "O Lord, how much longer til you come and rescue us?"
他们的灵魂向上帝呼求：“主啊，你还要多久才能来救我们？”
The answer comes back from Heaven
答案从天而降
"You must wait until your brothers have also suffered as you have."
“你必须等到你的兄弟也像你一样受苦。”
Now, one theory is that they're all part of the same group, but only 144,000 of them are given a special seal.
现在，一种理论认为他们都属于同一个群体，但其中只有 144,000 人获得了特殊印章。
This seal appears to mark them for special protection during those three and a half years of great trouble.
这封印似乎标志着他们在这三年半的大麻烦中受到特殊保护。
In the 12th chapter of the Revelation; some believers are given the wings of an eagle
在启示录第 12 章；一些信徒得到了鹰的翅膀
carrying them into the wilderness where they will escape much of the suffering.
将他们带到旷野，在那里他们将摆脱大部分苦难。
Could this be the 144,000? Possibly.
这可能是 144,000 吗？可能。
The Bible says that they'll be nourished there for three and a half years.
圣经说他们会在那里受养三年半。
If there really are two different groups, it would be helpful to know the difference between them.
如果真的有两个不同的组，了解它们之间的区别会很有帮助。
And then there's the obvious question we're probably all asking ourselves.
然后有一个显而易见的问题，我们可能都在问自己。
How would we get into the special group...the one that is going to be supernaturally protected and fed?
我们如何进入特殊群体……将受到超自然保护和喂养的群体？
The Hebrew Prophet, Amos, may have been referring to this elite group of people when he said
希伯来先知阿莫斯 (Amos) 说的可能是指这个精英群体
"Whatever the lord God plans to do he tells his servants, the prophets."
“无论主神计划做什么，他都会告诉他的仆人，即先知。”
The prophets, as a class of people, are those who can see clues about what is coming.
先知作为一类人，是能够看到即将发生的事情的线索的人。
Those who will take action to prepare for it, like the wise virgins did by taking extra oil for their lamps.
那些会采取行动为此做好准备的人，就像聪明的童女为他们的灯多加油一样。
The others were foolishly optimistic
其他人愚蠢地乐观
risking everything on the best possible scenario...they did not have a back-up plan.
在最好的情况下冒一切风险……他们没有备用计划。
Jesus said to his 12 apostles, "I have explained the secrets about the kingdom of heaven to you, but not to others.
耶稣对他的十二使徒说：“天国的奥秘我已经给你们讲解了，没有给别人讲解。
"Everyone who has something will be given more
“每个有东西的人都会得到更多
"but people who don't have anything will lose even what little they have."
“但一无所有的人，即使拥有的也很少。”
If having something means being prepared to follow Jesus wherever he goes
如果有东西意味着准备好跟随耶稣，无论他去哪里
like those 12 Apostles did, and like the Bible says the 144,000 will do
就像那 12 位使徒所做的，就像圣经所说的 144,000 人会做的
then I'm afraid that most of the church world today does not have anything like that.
那么恐怕今天大部分的教会世界都没有这样的东西。
They simply are not prepared.
他们根本就没有准备好。
Even those who say they know we are going to have to go through the tribulation
甚至那些说他们知道我们将要经历苦难的人
do virtually nothing about changing their lifestyle now, neither in preparation for the Great Tribulation
现在几乎没有改变他们的生活方式，也没有为大灾难做准备
nor in obedience to Jesus, as true followers of Jesus today.
也不服从耶稣，作为今天耶稣的真正追随者。
In fact, almost all of them choose deliberately and stubbornly
事实上，几乎所有的人都是刻意而固执地选择
day after day, not to obey the teachings of Jesus.
日复一日，不听从耶稣的教导。
They have substituted the teachings of their various denominations and pastors for the teachings of Jesus.
他们用不同教派和牧师的教义代替了耶稣的教义。
What I'm suggesting here
我在这里的建议
is that only those people who have chosen to follow the lamb (that is, Jesus) right now
是只有那些现在选择跟随羔羊（即耶稣）的人
before the trouble starts, are going to know where to go when it comes time to flee into that wilderness.
在麻烦开始之前，他们会知道该逃到那片荒野时该去哪里。
I am suggesting that they are the ones who have learned to hear from God
我建议他们是那些学会聆听上帝的人
and they have learned to act on what they hear.
他们已经学会了根据所听到的采取行动。
The wings of an eagle mentioned in Revelation 12 may just be the voice of God's spirit
启示录 12 章中提到的鹰的翅膀可能就是神灵的声音
calling them out of Babylon and into that wilderness retreat
呼唤他们离开巴比伦，进入旷野撤退
where they will experience God's miraculous provision.
他们将在那里经历神奇妙的供应。
Have you ever heard of birds starving to death in a famine? Of course not.
你听说过鸟在饥荒中饿死吗？当然不是。
The birds can see the signs that things are drying up, so they go elsewhere before it's too late.
鸟儿可以看到事情正在干涸的迹象，所以他们会在为时已晚之前去其他地方。
I'm sure that's what God wants us to do.
我相信这就是神要我们做的。
Can you see in the churches the signs of apostasy that mark this period In history?
你能在教会中看到标志着这段历史的背道迹象吗？
Are you prepared to flee?
你准备好逃离了吗？
Are you prepared to follow the Lamb instead or will you continue to delay in double-mindedness?
你准备好跟从羔羊，还是会在心怀二意的情况下继续拖延？
Jesus discussed with his 12 disciples this time when his true followers will flee at a moment's notice.
这一次，耶稣与他的 12 个门徒讨论了他的真正追随者何时会立即逃离。
They asked him, "But where will they go?" And Jesus said, "The eagles go where the food is."
他们问他：“但是他们要去哪里呢？”耶稣说：“鹰飞到食物所在的地方。”
Notice that word 'eagles'?
注意到“鹰”这个词了吗？
Some have called them vultures, but whether it's a nice word we use
有些人称它们为秃鹫，但我们是否使用了一个好词
or a nasty one, it is talking about scavengers.
或令人讨厌的，它在谈论清道夫。
A bird that survives on the scraps of a violent society, and it's talking about God's supernatural provision
一只在暴力社会的残骸上生存的鸟，它在谈论上帝的超自然供应
during the great tribulation.
在大患难中。
We may, like the eagles and vultures
我们可能像老鹰和秃鹰
literally survive on roadkill, but the main thing, one way or another, is that we will survive.
从字面上看，在路上被杀，但最重要的是，不管怎样，我们都会生存下来。
But only if we can be like the eagles.
但前提是我们能像老鹰一样。
They follow their God-given instincts and leave the system
他们遵循上帝赋予的本能并离开系统
before the famine--or in our case, a famine for the word of God--before it destroys them.
在饥荒之前——或者在我们的例子中，是对上帝话语的饥荒——在它摧毁他们之前。
In Luke Chapter 21, Jesus says, "Watch and pray always
在路加福音 21 章，耶稣说：“时时警醒祷告
"that you may be counted worthy to escape all these things that shall come to pass
“使你被认为有资格逃避这一切将要发生的事情
"and to stand before the Son of Man."
“并站在 b在人子之前。”
I'm not talking about the kind of escapism that pre-tribulation rapture offers.
我不是在谈论灾难前被提所提供的逃避现实。
I do think we all must face the possibility of dying for our faith.
我确实认为我们都必须面对为信仰而死的可能性。
But I also think that we make it worse for ourselves by putting such decisions off until it is too late
但我也认为我们把这样的决定推迟到为时已晚，这让我们自己变得更糟
for God to teach us everything we need to be learning right now.
因为上帝会教我们现在需要学习的一切。
We need to watch and pray now, knowing that there will be some
我们现在需要警醒祷告，知道会有一些
whom God will count worthy to escape into that wilderness during the great tribulation.
在大灾难期间，上帝会认为他们配得逃到旷野。
The Bible says, "Today is the day of salvation. Now is the acceptable time."
圣经说：“今天是得救的日子。现在是可以接受的时候。”
Jesus is looking for people who are hungering and thirsting after righteousness.
耶稣正在寻找饥渴慕义的人。
Not just an easy way out at the last minute.
不仅仅是在最后一分钟的简单出路。
People who will fast and pray until they find God's will.
会禁食祈祷直到找到上帝旨意的人。
People who will listen humbly to what he has been recorded as having said in the Bible
人们会谦卑地聆听他在圣经中所说的话
and who will obey him right now.
谁会立即服从他。
I don't see that happening anywhere, do you?
我在任何地方都没有看到这种情况发生，是吗？
Where can we find people who will watch and pray right now before the trouble starts?
我们在哪里可以找到在麻烦开始之前会立即观看和祈祷的人？
Where are the prophets who can see what is coming and who are willing to act on what they see?
那些能够看到即将发生的事情并愿意根据他们所看到的采取行动的先知在哪里？
Where are there people who would deny themselves, forsake all, and take up their cross to follow Jesus
哪里有舍己、撇下一切、背起十字架来跟从耶稣的人
taking no thought for food or clothing, but going into all the world to preach the Gospel instead?
不顾吃不穿，而是到全世界去传福音？
Laying our lives down for God and for one another: that is what God is calling on us to do now
为上帝和彼此舍命：这就是上帝现在呼召我们做的事
not at the last minute when we have no other choice.
不是在我们别无选择的最后一刻。
He wants us to freely choose to follow the lamb right now.
他要我们现在就自由选择跟随羔羊。
If my theory about these two groups is right
如果我关于这两个群体的理论是正确的
there may be a great multitude of people who will turn at the last minute.
可能有很多人会在最后一刻转身。
They could be the Christians who knew better all along
他们可能是自始至终都知道得更好的基督徒
but I think it's more likely they'll be converts from the un-churched masses
但我认为他们更有可能从非教会群众中皈依
who turned to God during the final seven years.
在最后七年转向上帝的人。
But whether these are professing Christians who suddenly decided to do what they failed to do
但这些是否是突然决定做他们没有做的自称是基督徒的人
in easier times, or whether they are converts from outside traditional Christianity
在更轻松的时期，或者他们是否从传统基督教之外皈依
like happened in the New Testament when God turned away from the Jews and toward the gentiles
就像在新约中发生的那样，当上帝离开犹太人而转向外邦人时
in either case, it does sound like these people...this great multitude
无论哪种情况，听起来确实像这些人……这么多人
that turns at the last minute, will not have the miraculous protection that the 144,000 will have.
到了最后一刻才转身，不会有十四万四千的神迹保护。
Some of them may starve to death, because they cannot buy food without the Mark of the Beast.
他们中的一些人可能会饿死，因为如果没有野兽的印记，他们就无法购买食物。
Some may freeze, some may die in other ways
有些可能会冻结，有些可能会以其他方式死亡
but it's just as likely they'll be executed for their faith before they have time to starve at least.
但至少在他们有时间挨饿之前，他们很可能会因为他们的信仰而被处决。
If they're unprepared, lukewarm churchgoers
如果他们毫无准备，不冷不热的礼拜者
it'll be as easy for this Antichrist to just walk into all the church buildings on a Sunday morning
对这个敌基督者来说，在周日早上走进所有的教堂建筑会很容易
and gun the lot of them down.
并枪杀他们中的很多人。
Wouldn't it be better to make your decision now?
现在做决定不是更好吗？
To turn away from the materialistic values of the world and the apostate church?
背离世界和背道教会的唯物主义价值观？
To follow Jesus into the wilderness of living by faith?
跟随耶稣进入凭信心生活的旷野？
I believe God is calling each of you to make a decision to start literally obeying Jesus
我相信上帝正在呼召你们每个人做出决定，开始真正顺服耶稣
like his first disciples did.
就像他的第一批门徒一样。
He has been calling us for 2,000 years, but time is running out.
2000 年来，他一直在呼唤我们，但时间不多了。
Will you join this prophetic movement in preparation for the return of Jesus?
你会加入这个预言运动，为耶稣的再来做准备吗？
Please pray about what I've said.
请为我所说的话祷告。
You can take a stand now, dedicating your life and all that you have to his service
你现在可以表明立场，把你的生命和你所有的一切都奉献给他的服务
or you can put off making such a decision until some more convenient time.
或者你可以推迟做出这样的决定，直到某个更方便的时间。
What will it be?
会是什么？
In a vision I say the souls that were slain for proclaiming the words of God.
在异象中，我说那些因宣讲上帝的话语而被杀的灵魂。
And they cried with a loud voice and this is what they said.
他们大声哭泣，这就是他们所说的。
Oh, Lord, how long must we wait, must we wait for your Kingdom?
哦，主啊，我们必须等待多久，我们必须等待你的王国吗？
And white robes were given to all of them, it was said to them that they should rest
并给了他们所有的白袍，据说他们应该休息
till their fellow servants should suffer as they did.
直到他们的同胞仆人像他们一样受苦。
Oh, Lord, how long must we wait, must we wait for your Kingdom?
哦，主啊，我们必须等待多久，我们必须等待你的王国吗？
Then I saw a multitude clothed in white which came out of the Great Tribulation.
然后我看见一大群人穿白衣，是从大灾难中出来的。
And they serve night and day, communing with the God of love.
他们日夜侍奉，与爱神交流。
Oh, Lord, how long must we wait, must we wait for your Kingdom?
哦，主啊，我们必须等待多久，我们必须等待你的王国吗？
They shall hunger no more, neither thirst any more, God shall wipe all tears form their eyes.
他们不再饥饿，不再口渴，上帝会擦去他们所有的眼泪。
For the Lamb shall feed them, and lead them to living waters.
因为羔羊要喂养他们，领他们到活水边。
Oh, Lord, how long must we wait, must we wait for your Kingdom?
哦，主啊，我们必须等待多久，我们必须等待你的王国吗？